So now let's talk about EBS snapshots.
So you can take your EBS volumes and make a snapshot,
which is also called a backup,
at any point of time that you wanted to.
The idea is that you will be able
to back up the state of it,
and even if the EBS volume is terminated later on,
you could restore it from that backup.
Now to make a backup, it is not necessary
to detach the volume prior to doing the backup,
but it is recommended just to make sure
that everything is clean on your EBS volume.
And why do we do snapshots?
Well, we can obviously restore them
but we can also copy snapshots
across availability zones or regions,
and the idea is that you would be able to transfer
some of your data in a different region on AWS
to leverage the global infrastructure.
So if we look at US-EAST-1A,
and we want to transfer an EBS volume to US-EAST-1B,
the way we do it is that we would have the EBS volume
attached to the EC2 instance, and then we would snapshot it.
So maybe we would stop the EC2 instance ahead of time
to make sure the snapshot is clean
or we could just do it on the fly.
It is really up to you and based on how you have programmed
your EC2 instance.
Now the EBS snapshots exist in your region.
And that EBS snapshot can be used
to restore a new EBS volume in another availability zone.
And then now that this is done,
we can attach the new EBS volume
to an EC2 instance in US-EAST-1B.
And there we go.
We have successfully and effectively transferred
an EBS volume through a snapshot across AZ.
So some features need to know about for EBS Snapshots
is the first one, an EBS snapshot archive.
So it allows you to move your snapshots
to another storage tier called an archive tier,
and that tier is 75% cheaper.
So your snapshot is going to be moved,
you know, manually or whatever, however you set
to the archive tier.
But if you have it in the archive,
it takes you between 24 to 72 hours
to restore from the archive.
So these are for snapshot
that are not very important to you
to restore it in a rush, okay,
but you wanna save some cost on them.
The second feature is around recycle bin for EBS snapshots.
So by default, when you delete snapshots, they're gone.
But you can set up a recycle bin,
and the recycle bin will have all the snapshots
that are deleted.
And then after a while, maybe you can specify
from one day to one year,
the snapshots are gone from the bin.
So on deleting the snapshots, it would go into recycle bin.
And you may have, for example, one year
to recover the snapshots, which allows you
to protect yourself against accidental deletion.
Okay.
That's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it
and I will see you in the next lecture.