So let's go ahead and practice using AMX.
For this, I'm going to launch an instance,
and I'm going to go into this new experience.
So I will scroll down.
We'll choose Amazon Linux 2.
I will scroll down again.
We'll use the G2 micro.
I will select the easy to draw as my key pair
but it doesn't really matter.
Then I will scroll down.
I would edit the network settings
and I will select an existing security group
being my launch wizard one from before.
Then we'll have the same storage and for advanced details,
I will scroll down and I will go for user data,
but this time you're going to copy everything,
but the last line.
So, in the first four lines, we actually install HTTPD
which is the Apache web server.
In the last line, we create an index file
but right now we don't want to create an index file
want to do everything but that to create an AMI out of it.
So we just copy everything.
Remember, the last line is the system CTL command.
And then we launch our instance.
So our instance is launched and what's going to happen is
that the instance is going to launch that's right here.
And then it's going to run
through the EC two, using the script
and it's going to install the Apache web server.
So if I'm too quick
and I try to open right now, this public IPV four
and try to enter into it, as you can see, it doesn't work.
I'll get a connection, error, refused and so on.
I need to make sure I'm also using the HTTP protocol,
of course, but it, it just won't work, right?
Because you need to give it a bit of time.
Even if it says 'running', you need to give it time
for the EC two user data script to run for the first time.
So this might take a minute.
This might take two minutes.
Okay. But don't be in a rush, just wait for it to be done.
And then at some point when you refresh
you will see the screen.
So let me pause the video.
And it took about two minutes, but now I have my test page
and this is the basic page from the Apache web server.
And therefore we are good to go.
So what we're going to do out of it is we're going to
create an AMI because we want to just save the state
of our EC two instance and reuse that.
So I right click and I will do image and templates
and then I will create an image.
So we'll call this one 'demo image'
and we're going to create our own AMI.
And then we have these settings right here.
We'll just leave it as is.
Go here and click on create image.
So now what's going to happen is that
an AMI is going to be created.
So if I go to the left-hand side and click on AMI's,
as we can see here, my demo AMI is registered.
And right now the status is pending
because it is being created.
So what I need to do is to be a little bit patient and
for it to go into the created state.
So my Amazon AMI is now created.
And what I can do now is I can launch instances
from this AMI by clicking here.
Or if you are in the instance creation page,
we can launch instances.
And this one is called 'From AMI'.
And in here in the quick start
we get access to the ones we know
but you can also go into the 'my AMI's tab'.
Okay. And you have the ones owned by me
and you can choose the demo image that you just created
from before.
So in that case, you scroll down, you select
to key pair or not, just up to you.
Network settings, again,
we edit them and we just select the existing launchers
in one security group.
And what I'm going to do is that in the advanced,
at the very bottom, I'm going to enter some user data.
So I copy the first three lines, okay.
Which are starting with the hash.
And then the last line, which is the echo on the new line.
And so what we do is that we only just write a new file.
So we don't need to reinstall HTTPD
because this AMI already contains HTTPD
which is why we will speed up in the boot up time.
This is why you would create an AMI.
So we launch an instance and now the instance is launched.
So I can just click on it.
This is the one from the AMI.
I need to wait for it to be fully created.
My instance from my AMI is now running.
I take the public IP address
and then I see the 'Hello World' from this.
And as you can see, this was much quicker
because we didn't have to install HTTPD again.
So this is the whole power of AMI's.
And you can imagine, well, it could be just more than that.
It could be security software,
a lot of prerequisite software, and so on,
you install it, it maybe it takes two,
three minutes to do it.
Then you package it as an AMI,
and then you just start from the AMI,
maybe do some end customization at the end
but you have a much faster boot-up.
And you're good to go.
So that's it for this demo.
Now to get back from this
what you do is that you take your two instances
and you can terminate them.
And that's it.
I will see you in the next lecture.