Now, here's a third type of storage
you can attach onto an EC2 instance.
And this is a network file system or NFS.
So, EFS stands for elastic file system
and it is a managed network file system.
And the idea and the benefits of it
is that it can be mounted to hundreds
of EC2 instances at a time.
So, before we had an EBS volume attached
to only one EC2 instance at a time.
But with an EFS drive, you can mount it
onto hundreds of EC2 instances.
So, that makes it a shared network file system
or shared NFS.
So, EFS works only with your Linux EC2 instances.
And on top of it, it works
across multiple availability zones.
So, it is possible for an instance
in one AZ to be attaching the same EFS volume
as the instance in another AZ.
Now, EFS is highly available, scalable, pretty expensive.
It's about three times the price of a gp2 EBS volume,
but you pay per use and you don't plan for capacity.
So, that means that if you store 20 gigabytes of data
onto your EFS drive then you're only going to pay
for these 20 gigabytes.
So, if you look at the diagram, this is very easy.
We have an EFS file system with a security group,
and then we have EC2 instances
in various availability zones connected to it.
So, we have EC2 instances in us-east-1a,
EC2 instances in us-east-1b,
as well as EC2 instances in us-east-1c.
And they're all connected to the same EFS File system.
So now, let's outline the exact differences
between EBS and EFS.
So, with EBS, say we had EC2 instance
in one AZ and another one.
Then the EBS volume can only be attached
to one instance in one specific AZ.
And the EBS volumes are bound
to specific availability zones.
But if we wanted to move over the EBS volume
from one AZ to another, we could create a snapshot,
it would create an EBS snapshot
and then restore that snapshot into a new availability zone.
And effectively we would've moved the EBS volume over.
But this is a copy, this is not an in-sync replica.
This is a copy, and that would mean
that this drive can now be used by another EC2 instance.
EFS is a network file system.
That means that whatever is on the EFS drive
is shared by everything that is mounted to it.
So, what does that mean?
Say we have many instances in Availability Zone 1 on one
or many instances as well on Availability Zone 2.
At the same time, all these instances
can mount the same EFS drive, okay,
using a mount target, and they will all see the same files.
So, that makes it a shared file system.
So, hopefully that makes it a very easy way
to understand the difference between EBS and EFS.
And this is something that the exam will test you on.
There is a storage class you need to know for EFS
and it's called EFS infrequent access or EFS-IA.
So, storage class is going to be cost-optimized
for files that you don't access very often.
So, for example, you don't access these files every day.
And this storage class will give you
upto 92% lower cost for storing the data
compared to the other surge class,
which is called EFS standard.
And if you enable EFS-IA, then EFS
will automatically move your files to EFS-IA,
based on the last times they were accessed
and something called a lifecycle policy.
So, let's take an example.
We have our EFS file system.
We have three files in EFS standard
and maybe a fourth file in EFS standard.
This one hasn't been accessed for 60 days,
that means that no one has read this file.
And no one has been writing to this file either, right?
So, if you define your lifecycle policy
and you enable EFS-IA, then for example, you can say,
hey, after 60 days, please move this file
to a different storage class which is called EFS-IA,
which is going to have some cost saving.
And this is going to be done automatically.
Now, next time you access this file,
it's going to be be put back into EFS standard
because it's more accessed more often, right?
So, the idea is that this is a cost saving optimization.
And from an application perspective,
there is really no drawbacks.
It's very transparent to the applications,
that means that your applications don't even need
to know where the file is if it's an EFS standard,
or EFS-IA, it will access all these files the same way.
It's just behind the scenes,
EFS will do some cost optimizations.
So, something to need to know, going to your exam.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.