As usual, shared responsibility is important
going into the certified cloud practitioner exam.
And so we need to understand where is the responsibility
for AWS and yours regarding EC2 storage.
So AWS, of course, is responsible for their infrastructure,
but also because in the technical specification of EBS, EFS,
the tell you the data is replicated across many hardware,
it is AWS responsibility to perform that replication.
So that if one day some hardware is not working,
you as a customer is not impacted.
Also, anytime an EBS drive would fail,
or one part of it would fail.
It is obviously AWS responsibility
to replace that faulty hardware.
And finally, because we're talking about data storage,
it is their responsibility to ensuring that their employees
cannot access your data.
Now what is your responsibility as a customer?
Well, setting up any backup or snapshot procedures
and guidelines is very important to ensure
that you don't lose your data.
Setting up data encryption is another layer of protection
to ensure that people cannot have access to your data,
would it be AWS or other customers of AWS,
even though obviously,
security would be in place for it not to happen,
but it would be an interesting second layer of security.
Any data you set,
obviously, on the drive is your responsibility.
Anything you write to that disk is your own responsibility.
And if you're using an EC2 instance store,
you need to understand the risks
that are associated with it,
which is that you can lose the drive if somehow
there's a faulty hardware,
or that if you stop or terminate the EC2 instance
that has an instant store,
then the data will be lost.
So again, it would be responsibility
to back it up in the first place.
Okay, that's it, I hope that was helpful
and I will see you in the next lecture.