Okay, so now let's talk about Amazon FSx,
which is a managed service to get third-party
high-performance file systems on AWS.
So in case you don't wanna use EFS or S3,
and you want something else, then you can use FSX
to manage these file systems.
So you have three offerings today.
You have FSx for Lustre, FSx for Windows File Server,
and FSx for NetApp ONTAP.
And they can add file systems over time
to the FSx service, I'm pretty sure,
but they will not update this video
unless you need to know about the other ones.
So the two most important ones are going to be
FSx for Lustre, and FSx for Windows File Server,
and this is what is covered in this lesson.
The first one is Amazon FSx for Windows File Server,
which is a fully managed, highly reliable and scalable
Windows native shared file system
built on Windows File Server.
So this is meant for Windows instances.
So the way you do it is that deploy the FSx
usually across two availability zones,
and then there is support
for all the Windows native protocols,
such as the SMB protocol and Windows NTFS,
which allows you to mount this file system
onto your Windows machines.
And so if you look at your corporate data center
and you have a Windows Client, for example,
over SMB, it's able to access the Windows file server.
But also if you had EC2 instances that are Windows based,
and then they could also might as well
access this Windows file server.
So Amazon FSx is the way to deploy this Windows file server
that leverages the SMB protocol and Windows NTFS.
Because this is also a Microsoft type of offering,
there is integration with Microsoft Active Directory
for user security and Windows file server in Amazon FSx
can be accessed from AWS directly,
or as you can see on this diagram
from your on-premises infrastructure.
Now, the second flavor of Amazon FSx you have in AWS
is called Amazon FSx for Lustre.
And you need to remember that this says to have
a fully managed, high-performance and scalable file storage
for high performance computing.
So whenever you see storage for HPC,
so high-performance computing, thinks FSx for Lustre.
Why, well Lustre, there is derived from the name
Linux and cluster, so put together it's Lustre.
And so imagine cluster like processing
this kind of things, maybe it's a way for you to remember
what Amazon FSx for Lustre is.
This allows you to run a lot of use cases
for high performance computing, such as machine learning,
analytics, video processing, financial modeling,
and it scales to extremely high traffics
in terms of hundreds of gigabytes per second
of data exchanged, millions of IO operations per second,
sub milliseconds latency,
so it's really a high-performance file system.
So the way it works is that Amazon FSx for Lustre
can be connected either to your corporate data center
or to your compute instances directly within AWS.
And then in the backend, Amazon FSx for Lustre
is actually storing your data,
possibly onto an Amazon S3 bucket.
So that's it, that's all you need to know for Amazon FSx
there is no easy hands-on to do it.
So we'll skip that, but just remember the two flavors
of Amazon FSx going into the exam,
and you should be good to go.
So that's it, I will see you in the next lecture.