So let's summarize what we have learned in this section.
The first one around the EBS volumes,
they are network drives that are attached
to one EC2 instance at a time.
They're mapped to a specific Availability Zone
and we can use the EBS snapshot feature to do backups
or to be able to transfer the data from one EBS volume
across to an other Availability Zone.
We've seen about AMIs.
There are ready to use EC2 instances images, with
the customizations we want.
And if we want to automate the process of building an AMI
we can use the EC2 image builder service to
automatically build tests and distribute AMIs.
We've seen EC2 instance store, which is a way
for us to have a very high performance hardware disc
this time, attached to our EC2 instance.
But it is lost
in case our instances stopped or terminated.
If we wanted to have a network file system,
we would use the EFS service.
With EFS service,
we can get a NFS that we can attach
to hundreds of instances within the region.
So there is no AZ luck,
now it's at the region level.
And if you want to cost-optimize our EFS service,
we could use EFS-IA,
which allows us to move the files that are infrequently used
into a lower cost tier.
Finally, we've seen about FSx, FSx for Windows,
which is a way for us to get a network file system
for Windows servers
and FSx for Luster, which is
for us to perform high performance computing.
So HPC on a Linux file system.
So to say for this section, I hope you liked it
and that I will see you in the next section.