Now that we have created users in groups,
it is time for us to protect these users
in groups from being compromised.
So for this, we have two defense mechanisms.
The first one is to define
what's called a password policy.
Why?
Well, because the stronger the password you use,
the more security for your accounts.
So in AWS you can set up a password policy
with different options.
The first one is you can set a minimum
password length and you can
require specific character types.
For example, you may want
to have an uppercase letter, lowercase letter,
number, non alphanumeric characters,
for example, a question mark and so on.
Then you can allow or not IAM users
to change their own passwords,
or you can require users to change their password
after some time to make your password expired,
for example, to say every 90 days,
users have to change their passwords.
Finally, you can also prevent password reuse
so that users, when they change their passwords,
don't change it to the one
that they already have or change it
to the one they had before.
So this is great.
A password policy really is helpful
against brute force attacks on your account.
But there's a second defense mechanism
that you need to know going into the exam.
And this is the Multi-Factor Authentication or MFA.
It is possible, you already used it
on some websites, but on AWS it's a must
and it's very recommended to use it.
So users have access to your account
and they can possibly do a lot of things,
especially if they're administrators.
They can change configuration,
delete resources and other things.
So you absolutely want to protect
at least your root account and hopefully,
all your IAM users.
So how do we protect them on top of the password?
Well, you use an MFA device.
So what is MFA?
MFA is using the combination of a password
that you know and a security device that you own.
And these two things together
have a much greater security
than just a password.
So for example, let's take Alice.
Alice knows her password,
but she also has an MFA generating token.
And by using these things together
while logging in, she's going to be able
to do a successful login on MFA.
So the benefit of MFA is that even if Alice
has lost her password
because it's stolen or it's hacked,
the account will not be compromised
because the hacker will need to also get a hold
of the physical device of Alice,
that could be her phone, for example,
to do a login.
Obviously that is much less likely.
So what are the MFA devices option in AWS?
And you need to know them going into the exam,
but don't worry, they're quite simple.
The first one is a virtual MFA device.
This is what we'll be using in the hands-on.
And so you can use Google Authenticator,
which is just working on one phone at a time,
or using Authy.
So for Authy, you have support
for multiple tokens on a single device.
So that means that with the virtual MFA device,
you can have your root account,
your IAM user, another account, another IAM user.
It's up to you.
You can have as many users and accounts
as you want on your virtual MFA device,
which make it a very easy solution to use.
Now we have another thing
called a Universal 2nd Factor
or U2F Security Key,
and that is a physical device.
For example, a YubiKey by Yubico
and Yubico is a third party to AWS.
This is not AWS that provides it.
This is a third party.
And we use a physical device
because maybe it's super easy,
you put it on your key fobs
and you're good to go.
So this YubiKey supports multiple root
and IAM users using a single security key.
So you don't need as many keys as users,
otherwise there will be a nightmare.
Then you have other options.
You have a hardware key fob MFA device,
for example, this one provided by Gemalto,
which is also a third party to AWS.
And finally, if you are using the cloud
of the government in the US, the AWS GovCloud,
then you have a special key fob
that looks like this
that is provided by SurePassID,
which is also a third party.
So that's it.
We've seen the theory
on how to protect your account,
but let's go in the next lecture
to implement that.
So I will see you in the next lecture.