So we are going to first,
define a password policy.
For this, click on account settings on the left-hand side.
You will find password policy and you can edit it.
So here, we can use the IAM default password policy,
which composes of these kind of requirements,
or we can customize the password policy
and force a password minimum length.
We can also require uppercase letter, lowercase letter,
a number, a non-alphanumeric character.
We can also turn on password expiration to turn on,
for example, expire after 90 days,
or that a password expiration
requires administrative resets, or we can allow the users
to change their own password
or we can prevent password reuse.
So this password process can be edited directly
from the IAM console, and that's the first part of security.
The second part
is around setting multi-factor authentication
for your root account.
So if you click on the account name
and then click on security credentials, if you are logged in
with the root user,
you will see my security credentials root user.
Now, there is a way for you
to actually protect your root user,
which is the most important account in your AWS account,
and you can protect it by using multi-factor authentication.
Now, just so you know, I'm going to do it
and demonstrate how it works in front of you,
but I've had students who locked themselves out
of their accounts because they lost access
to their multi-factor authentication device.
As such, if you think you are running the risk
of losing your iPhone or whatever, do not do this, okay?
Just keep your phone with you, just watch my video.
It will be good enough if you want to practice along
with me, you can as well.
And you can also delete the MFA device after activating it.
Okay, but let's go ahead and assign an MFA device.
So I will call this one my iPhone
because this is what I have, but you can name it
whatever you want.
Then you can select the type of MFA device.
So it could be an authenticator app,
which is something I'm going to use,
but also it can be a security key or a hardware TOTP token.
So I'm going to use an authenticator app
because it will be virtual.
And now we go into the setup of the app.
So there's a list of compatible applications right here.
You can find here for Android
and for iOS that we know work well with AWS.
And as such, I'm going to use the Twilio
of the Authenticator, which is an app I like.
So what I have to do then is actually launch the app
on my phone and then you click on show QR code.
So when you should a QR code, you need
to scan this QR code directly on your phone.
So for this, you add an account,
you scan the QR code right here,
and once scanned, it will add the account
and start naming it.
So we'll just save this, this looks good.
And then we get access to MFA code.
So there is first, the first MFA code, so 301935.
So this is a code generated by my iPhone in real-time.
And this code is going to change over time.
And the reason why these two codes are asked by AWS
is that it wants to make sure that the MFA device
is set up correctly and that the codes are accurate.
So the second code is 792843.
And, of course, there will be difference for your device.
And once these two codes are entered, you click on add MFA.
And as you can see, we can reach there up
to eight MFA devices currently, and you can scroll down
and see them right here on the list.
So the multi-factor authentication, MFA, one,
it's called my iPhone that's been created right now.
So if you wanted to remove it, you can remove it and so on.
But so how do we use MFA?
Well now, if I log out of AWS
and I log back in, so I'm going
to use my router account and my password.
Now after doing a successful login,
I have the MFA code to enter.
And so I open my app
and enter the code that I see and press submit.
And this way IAM logged in.
And this is perfect because well, we had an extra level
of security on our account.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.