Okay so we are going to install
the aws command line on Windows.
So for this we do aws CLI install windows on Google.
And this will give us the list link
and we want to install the aws-cli version 2 on Windows.
Okay this is the latest and so we'll up to dates.
It doesn't change much versus version 1,
it is just some improved performance and capability,
but the API's exactly the same
and there's also an improved installer.
So I'm going to scroll down,
in here and to Install on Windows
where you can just simply
install it using the MSI installer,
so I just click on this link to download the MSI installer.
then I'm going to run the installer
so it should very very simple.
Now the installer is starting,
I click on Next.
I accept the terms of the license,
click on Next,
Install and then we wait for the installer to be done.
Yes, I want to allow whatever this is doing.
Okay so the installer is now complete.
I click on Finish
and now I can go ahead and open a command line,
so I'll do command line,
Command Prompt here we go on Windows,
and to be sure that it's fully installed
I just type aws--version
and press enter,
and if you get a result like this:
aws-cli, a version that starts with a 2,
then Python, Windows,
that means that your aws-cli
is now properly installed on Windows
and you're good to go.
Finally just note that if you want to upgrade your aws-cli
then you just need to re-download that MSI installer
and just re-run the install
and it will be automatically upgraded.
But as soon as you have this output you're good to go
and you can follow me in the next lecture.
So see you in the next lecture.