So let's practice using roles.
So on the left hand side, you click on roles,
and you can see that some roles may have already
been created for your accounts.
Could be two, could be more. It doesn't matter.
But what we're going to do is that we're going to
create our own role in here.
So a role is a way to give AWS entities permissions
to do stuff on AWS.
As you can see, you have different kind of roles.
You can create actually five of them right now.
But the one that you need to know about for this hands-on
and for the exam is going to be a role for an AWS service.
So let's choose this one, and then we need to choose
for which service we want this role to apply to.
So as you can see, if you click on it,
you have commonly used services, such as EC2 and Lambda,
or a role for pretty much every service on AWS.
So it's a very common thing to know in AWS,
and that's why we learn about it.
So we are going to create a role for an EC2 instance
when we get to the EC2 section.
And so we choose EC2, and the use case is just EC2.
We disregard any of these.
So click on next, and now that we create a role
for an EC2 instance, we need to attach a policy.
So I'm going to attach the IAM read only access
to allow my EC2 instance to read whatever is in IAM.
Let's click on next.
Next do meet to enter a demo, a role name,
so DemoRoleForEC2 is going to be my role name,
and then we select the trusted entities.
So this is saying, hey, this role can be assumed
by the EC2 service, and this is what defines it
as a role for Amazon EC2.
We are verifying the permissions,
yes, it has IAM read only access,
and we create this role.
So now my role is created.
As you can see, it appears in my role lists.
And we can verify that the permissions
are correct for this role.
Now, we cannot use this role just yet
because we need to get to the EC2 section,
but we will use it when we get to it.
In the meantime, you've seen how to create a role
for Amazon EC2 and how to attach correct permissions to it.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.