We are nearing the end of the section,
but first let's talk about the kind of security tools
we have in IAM.
So we can create an IAM Credentials Report
and this is at your account-level.
This report will contain all your accounts users
and the status of their various credentials.
We'll be actually generating it right now
and having a look at it.
The second security tool we're gonna use in IAM
is called IAM Access Advisor.
This one is at the user-level
and the Access Advisor is going to show
the service permissions granted to a user
and when those services were last accessed.
This will be very helpful because we are talking already
about the principle of least privilege,
and so using this tool, we're able to see which permissions
are not used and reduce the permission a user can get
to be inline with the principle of least privilege.
So I will see you in the next lecture
to show you how to use the security tools.