So let's generate a credentials report.
For this, on the left hand side,
I just click on Credential report
and then Download credential report
which is going to create a CSV file.
Now this CSV, because I'm using a training account,
is not fascinating,
but as we can see we have two rows in it.
We have my root account and my account name, stephane.
We can see when the user was created,
if the password was enabled,
when the password was last used and last changed,
when is the next rotation to be expected
if we do enable password rotation?
Is MFA active?
So we can see it's active from my root accounts
but it is not active for my Stefane accounts.
Then access keys, are they generated or not?
Yes, they're created for my Stefane account,
but not for my root account,
and when they were last rotated, last used and so on,
you can get more information about other access keys
and certificates and so on.
So this report is extremely helpful
if you want to look at some users
that haven't been changing the password,
or using it, or their account,
it could be giving you a great way to find which users
that deserve your attention from a security standpoint.
Now let's have a look at IAM Access Advisor.
For this, I'm gonna go to my user, stephane,
and then on the right hand side, I click on Access Advisor.
And Access Advisor is going to show me
which services were accessed by my user and when.
So as you can see, organizations, health,
identity and access managers with IAM Service,
EC2, Resource Explorer, were all accessed by my user.
So I use my user to access these things
by clicking in the UI, but some services were not accessed,
for example, Alexa for Business
or AWS App2Container and so on.
So using Access and Advisor, you can actually have a look
at whether or not the user has the correct permissions.
And it turns out that maybe based on this access,
have 37 pages of this,
maybe the user needs access only to a few services
but not all of them.
And this UI allows you to drill down.
On top of it, if a user accesses a specific service
for example Amazon EC2, we are told
that this is the administrator access
that granted access to this service.
So to summarize, Access Advisor becomes very helpful
when you need to do granular user access permissions on AWS.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.