Throughout the CCP exam, you are going
to get a lot of questions on something called
Shared Responsibility Model.
And this is to ensure that you know
what AWS is responsible for,
and what you are responsible for.
Now, I want to include some bits of information
within some sections to give you an idea of how
the shared responsibility model works for AWs.
So AWS is responsible for everything
that they do, for example, their infrastructure
and their global network security,
the configuration and vulnerabilty analysis
of the services they offer,
and any sign of compliance
that they are responsible for.
But regarding IAM, you are responsible for a lot
of things that AWS will not do for you.
You are responsible for creating your own users,
your groups, your roles, your policies,
the management of these policies,
and the monitoring of that.
You are responsible for enabling MFA
on all accounts and enforcing this, not AWS.
You are also responsible to make sure
that the keys are rotated often.
You need to make sure that you use the IAM tools
to apply the appropriate permissions,
and again, you are responsible
for analyzing the access patterns
and review the permissions in your accounts,
not AWS.
So this is a very simple example,
but an obvious one. But AWS is responsible
for all the infrastructure,
and you are responsible for how you use
that infrastructure.
This is just one of these lectures
on shared responsibility.
I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.