Okay, so now let's talk
about EC2 Instance Types.
So there are different types of EC2 instances
that you can use for different use cases
and they have different types of optimization.
And let's go check out this link
and we'll see we have for now,
seven different types of EC2 instances.
So this website on the AWS website
is what we're interested into.
And as we can see, we have different types of instances.
We have general purpose, compute, optimized,
memory optimize and so on.
And so for each type of instance
we have different families.
And so as we can see this website is going to
be the reference for us to look at Institute Instance types
and know their costs and other specificity.
What I'm going to do though, is just walk you
through a high-level overview of how they work in AWS.
AWS will have the following naming convention.
For example, we'll be talking
about an M five dot two X large type of instance.
What does that mean?
Well, M is going to be called the Instance Class.
Okay. And this is going to be, for example, in this case
a general purpose type of instance,
five is generation of the instance.
So as AWS improves the hardware over time
if we release a new generation of hardware, and so
after M five, if they improve the M type of instance class
then we'll go to M six
and then finally the two X large represented the size
within the instance class.
So, it starts as small and then large
and then two X large four X large and so on.
So it represents the size of the instance,
and the more the size, the more the memory
the more the CPU is going to have on your instance.
So from an exam perspective, what do you need to know?
Well, we'll talk about a few different types
of instance types.
So you have a general purpose
and these are great for diversity of workloads
such as web servers or code repositories.
They will have a good balance
between compute, memory, networking.
And so in this course
we'll be using general purpose instances.
We'll be using the T2 micro
which is the free tier, general purpose type of instance.
On the website that I just showed you
you will see all the different types
of instance that our general purpose
and this is going to evolve over time,
So I won't update this slide.
But you can always refer back
to the AWS website to check what the instances are
in the general purpose type of family.
Then we have compute optimized,
and these are instances are great,
and optimized for compute intensive tasks.
So what requires a high level of processor?
Well, if, for example, it could be
if you're batch processing some data
if you're doing media transcoding
if you need a high-performance web servers
if you're doing high performance, computing is called HPC.
If you're doing machine learning
or if you have a dedicated gaming server.
So all these things are tasks that require a very good CPU
very good compute side.
And so Ec2,
instances do have this kind of particularity
and for now all the computer optimized instances
in EC2, are of the C names.
So C5, C6, and so on.
Next, we have some EC2 instances that are memory optimized
and there are going to be
have a really fast performance for the type
of workloads that will process large datasets in memory.
So memory means RAM.
And so the use cases are this is going to
be high performance for relational or
non-relational databases are mostly going to be
in memory databases,
distributed web-scale cache store.
So for our elastic cache, for example
in memory databases that are optimized
for business intelligence or BI.
And applications performing real-time processing
of big unstructured data.
So in terms of the names for the memory optimized instances
there's going to be the R series because R stands for RAM
but there's also going to be X one high memory and Z one,
but again, you don't have to remember the name
of the instances, but good to know at a high level.
Okay. And finally we'll have storage optimized instances.
They're great when you are accessing a lot
of data sets on the local storage.
And so the use cases for storage optimized instances
are going to be high-frequency online
transactional processing, so OLTP systems.
Relational and NoSQL databases.
And we'll see those in details.
When we get to the database sections.
Cache for in-memory databases, for example,
Reddit's data warehousing application
distributed file systems
and the search optimized instances in AWS
will start with an I, a G, or H one.
Okay. But again, don't have to remember this.
I'm just giving you examples.
So what does it mean?
Let's compare a few instance types.
So for example, for t2.micro
we have one VCPU and one memory, one gigabytes of memory.
And if you look for example, at r5.16xlarge
we have 16 VCPU and 512 gigabytes of memory.
So we can see there's a lot of more emphasis on the memory.
If we compare it to example, to a c5d.4Xlarge
we can see we have 16 VCPU and 32 gigabytes of memory.
So less memory, more CPU
and so on different network performance
different EBS bandwidth and so on.
So just to give you a point of comparison,
and because we're using t2.micro in this course
it is part of the AWS feature.
So we get up to 750 hours per month of t2.micro.
And if you want a website to compare all the
EC2 Institute instances together,
there's one that I really like,
it's called instituteinstance.info,
and I'll show it to you right now.
So I am on the instituteinstances.info website
and as we can see,
we have a list of all the instances available in AWS.
So really, a lot.
We also get some information around
the Linux on demand cost and an X reserves cost,
and so on, so some cost information.
We get information around the memory the number of VCPU.
We can order by name, we can search it.
So it's, it's quite handy.
And I really like this website.
And if you go and use AWS
you probably will use this website as well.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.