So I wanna talk about IPv4 charges in AWS.
So since February 1st, 2024, there is now a charge
for all Public IPv4 created in your account
whether or not they are being used.
And so you have a $0.005 per hour
of Public IPv4, which is about 3.6 dollars per month
whenever you have a Public IPv4 in your account.
So you have a Public IPv4 for example,
when you create an EC2 instance.
Now for the EC2 service,
for new accounts in AWS you have a free tier of 12 month,
and in the first 12 months of your account,
you will have 750 hours of Public IPv4 per month.
That means that when you go over,
you're going to pay, of course,
and for any other service than EC2,
there is no free tier, and you're going to pay that charge.
So it's a bit annoying.
So let me just try to do a diagram to explain to you.
So when we create an EC2 instance, we try to connect to it,
and so we'll have a public IP.
And so this is free until 750 hours per month of usage,
which is about a month.
If you create a second EC2 instance
and you also create a public IP for that EC2 instance,
then again this goes towards the 750 hours per month.
So you can have three, four EC2 instances,
it doesn't matter, as long as together,
the public IP usage is less than 750 hours per month,
you're good to go.
But if you go over, and you have four Public IPv4
for example, at the same time,
then of course you're going to pay for all of them
after this free tier.
When we go later on and create load balancers, for example,
then you may have one Public IPv4 per AZ.
So if you launch a load balancer in three AZ,
you'll have three Public IPv4.
Here, there is no free tier,
and so you will have charges incurred
while using a load balancer.
So it's a good idea to, if you wanna create it,
know that you'll have charges,
and know that you won't delete it fast enough
after doing the hands-on.
For an Amazon RDS Database for example, again,
this is not the EC2 service.
So when you create a database
and you want to connect to it from your public computer,
you will create a public IPv4 address,
and there is no free tier,
so you will have charges around it.
So just be mindful that you will have charges
in this course.
I said you would not,
but this is unfortunately a big change,
and there's no way around it.
So if you want to use any other service than EC2
and connect to it publicly,
you will have IPv4 addresses,
and you will have charges for it.
So please make sure
to never leave things running for too long.
Now you may ask me, "What about IPv6?"
So yes, the whole idea behind these charges for AWS is
that they're trying to migrate everything to IPv6,
where it's a bit easier to have them at scale.
And so in this course, I would love to use IPv6,
but it turns out that many internet service providers
around the world do not support IPv6 yet.
And so this course will not work for some of you.
So usually, you can go to an address like this,
for example, test-ipv6.com
to see if IPv6 is working for you.
But unfortunately, because, I mean, I am fortunate
to have so many millions of students around the world,
but it won't work for all of you,
then I'm not going to change the course for that reason.
So if you use IPv6 in this course on your own
because you want to avoid this tiny charge,
then you're on your own.
But know that you'll have to create
your own security group rules.
You make sure you make your own networking decisions,
but it's possible.
And if you know about networking, you will figure this out.
But if you're new to cloud computing, AWS, IT,
or networking in general, then keep on going with IPv4
and be mindful that you will have charges for IPv4.
Now, if you have charges, you may want to troubleshoot them,
so you need to go to your bill to see your charges.
And then there's a service
called the AWS Public Insights service that can help you.
And there's also a nice article that I've linked right here
that is explaining how you can troubleshoot these charges
if you can't figure out
which service still has an IPv4 address in use
and how you're being charged.
So just remember that if you have any cost,
you go under billing and cost management in your account,
and then you go under bills on the left hand side,
and you will have a bill summary.
And here you can see your charges by service
and understand what is costing you any kind of money
by just drilling down.
So here on the right hand side, you would have an amount,
and then you can expand everything
and see what the amount equates to.
So if you have IPv4 charges,
they will appear right here,
and it's important for you to understand them.
Also, if you want to see your IP addresses,
you type IPAM, I-P-A-M in here,
and you go to Amazon VPC IP Address Manager,
which is a feature in the VPC console.
And this is how you can monitor all your IP addresses
in your account and get some information.
So you can go clear and click on Public IP Insights.
And here, you need to create an IPAM,
and we're saying yes to everything.
We can use it in the free tier
just to get the Public IPv4 usage in your organization.
And then you would go ahead, select the regions you wanted.
So, you can add all the regions,
and then click on Create IPAM.
And this will give you some insights
into your public IPs being used.
This is within the free tier.
Again, we're here under the free tier.
And so under Public IP Insights,
you would get some information around your public IPs
once information has been gathered on it.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.