Now again,
one more reminder into the Shared Responsibility Model
and how this applies for EC2.
So AWS is going to be responsible for all data centers,
their infrastructure and the security of them,
then AWS is going to be responsible
for making sure you have isolation on the physical host,
if you're getting,
for example, a dedicated host or replacing faulty hardware
if one of their servers is failing,
or making sure they are still compliant with the regulations
that they have agreed to.
But you as a user,
you're responsible for the security in the cloud.
So that means that you define your own security group rules.
And this allows you or other people to access
or not your EC2 instances.
You own the entire virtual machine
inside of your EC2 instance.
So that means that your operating system will be Windows
or Linux, all the patches and the updates.
You have to do them not AWS.
AWS will give you the virtual machine.
It's up to you to handle it the way you want.
That means that all the software
and the utilities that are installed on this EC2 instance,
also are yours to be responsible for.
Finally, understanding how to assign AM Roles
and make sure the permissions are correct.
And finally, making sure data is secure on your instance
is also very important for your EC2 instances.
So that's it.
Hope that again puts a bit of perspective
on to the shared responsibility model for EC2
and I will see you in the next lecture.