Let's do a summary
on what we learned for EC2.
So we have created EC2 instances,
and they were composed of an AMI,
which was defining the operating system.
Then we defined an instance size where we defined
how much CPU power we want and how much RAM we want.
We described the storage for our EC2 instance.
We defined the firewall on our EC2 instance
with the security groups.
And finally, a bootstrap script called the EC2 User Data
that was started when the EC2 instance was started.
So the security groups are attached to EC2 instances,
and they are a firewall outside of your instance.
And you can define rules to allow which ports
and which IP can access your EC2 instance.
For EC2 user data, this was a script that we launched
at the first start of an instance that we used to set up
our EC2 instance to be a web server and say, "Hello, world."
SSH was our way for us to start a terminal
from our computers into our EC2 instances
to start issuing commands on port 22.
And once we did it, we were able to leverage
an EC2 instance role that was similar to an IAM role
to have our EC2 instance issue commands against IAM.
In terms of purchasing options,
you have multiple options you need to know for the exam.
You have on-demand, spot instances,
reserved instances for standard or convertible,
dedicated host, dedicated instance, and that's it.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.