Hello and welcome
to the AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner course.
My name is Stephane Maarek and I will be your instructor.
So we are starting in five minutes,
but please try to pay attention to this lecture.
So we are going to prepare for the Cloud Practitioner exam.
The exam code is CLF-C02.
It is a challenging certification
so this course is going to be long and interesting
and it is good if you have some basic IT knowledge,
but don't worry if you don't come from an IT background
I will explain everything for you as well.
In this course, we're going to learn a lot.
We will cover over 40 AWS services
out of the 200 plus that exists in AWS.
If you are a beginner in IT and AWS, do not worry.
You are welcome to this course
and you will learn a lot.
But take your time. It's not a race.
You'll learn a lot every day by doing little by little.
Then this course is a bit special,
because I want you to learn also by doing.
It's a key learning technique in this course.
So this course will mix both theory lectures
and where necessary, hands-on where you can follow along
with me in the course by creating your own AWS accounts
and reproducing what I do on screen.
So now we're preparing for a certification.
I want to show you the type
of questions you're going to get.
So this is a sample question from the exam
which says, "Which AWS service would simplify the migration
of a database to AWS?"
It will have four answers,
Storage Gateway, Database Migration Service,
EC2 and Amazon AppStream 2.0.
Now this course is going to cover most of the services.
For example, the first service we will learn in this course.
The second service, the name is obvious,
it is the answer to the question.
That is the correct answer
and we will cover this service as well.
For EC2, we will learn as well,
and it is possible in the course you have services
that will be called distractors.
So they will not be covered in the course
because there are over 200 services in AWS,
but they will appear at the exam as a wrong answer.
So in this course I want to focus on the service
that I know are core to AWS
and that will come up in the exam
but it will not focus on explaining you the distractors
because that would make too much information into your head.
If you're interested into checking out the sample questions
for the exam, you can use this link.
So now a little bit about me.
So my name is Stephane Maarek
and I will be your instructor for this course.
I have 11 AWS certifications, so all of them,
and I've worked with AWS for many years.
I've built websites, applications
streaming platforms and so on.
I've been teaching for almost seven years on Udemy
about AI certifications
or services CloudFormation, Lambda and EC2.
As you can see, I have over 2 million students
that have went through my courses
and everyone has been very successful with this course.
So I'm very happy that you're here
following along with me.
So you can connect with me on social media.
You can follow me on LinkedIn, on Instagram, on Medium,
Twitter and GitHub, and the links are here.
So welcome to AWS.
You are going to get certified
and you're going to get the first certification in AWS
called the Foundational certification
for AWS cloud practitioner.
This is a great first choice, but this is pretty high level.
If you want to deepen your knowledge
and get more technical about AWS.
Then after this course,
I would recommend you tackle the Associate certifications.
Then if you're really an aficionado of AWS
and want to learn more and more and more, the Specialty exam
and the Professional exams are really difficult
and will test your in-depth knowledge.
In this course, we're just going to prepare
for the foundational knowledge necessary to pass
with flying colors
the AWS certified cloud practitioner examination.
Finally, I said we are going to practice in this course.
So you may have a question,
which is how much will this course cost me?
So this is how much it costs me at the end of this course,
$12 and 70 cents.
But I wanna tell you right away
that most of the services we'll use
in this course will be within the AWS Free Tier.
So there is a chance for you to have a cost of zero.
Now, if I use a service
in this course that will cost you money, I will mention it
and I will give you the option to not do the hands-on
with me and just watch me do.
For example, the most expensive item
in here is the registrar because I purchased a domain name.
So a URL, for example, stephaneccp.com.
You can read more about the Free Tier at this URL
if you're unsure about if something is going
to cost you money or not
or you can just come back to the slide
and then see based on the service we're watching
if it's going to cost you anything or not.
As I mentioned, most of the services we'll be using
will be within the Free Tier, so don't worry there,
I'll be guiding you all along the way.
I am super happy that you're here with me in this course
and I wish you a happy learning.