So let's go ahead and create an AWS accounts.
And the first thing you have to do,
is to specify a route user email address
which is your main email address.
And they will be used to log to your Amazon accounts.
On top of it, you can specify a name for account.
For example, stefane-demo-v3.
After verifying your accounts,
you have to set a root user password
and confirm this root user password.
If you lose your root password,
you can recover it,
thanks to your email, but it is better for you not to forget
about your email address and your root user password.
Next, you specify that this is a personal accounts
and you enter your details for this accounts.
Next, you have to enter credit card details
and you will get an authorization
of $1 onto this credit card.
So this is not a charge, is a pending transaction
and it's just an authorization that will be canceled.
And as long as you remain within the Free Tier,
you will not be charged.
But if you go over the Free Tier, then you will be charged.
And I will show you of course
how out to monitor for these things.
But if you follow this course,
you should remain within the Free Tier limits.
After that step, you must confirm your identity
by providing a phone number and then receiving
either SMS or a voice call to confirm that phone number.
Then you must choose a support plan
and will use the basic support free for this course,
because that's all we need.
Then you complete the signup,
and congratulations you are signed up for AWS.
It will take a few minutes to activate your account
and you'll receive an email when this is complete.
In the meantime, you can click
on go to the AWS Management Console.
You must enter your root user email address
and your password, and then you are logged
in into the AWS Console.
Congratulations, let's get started with this course.