Welcome to Udemy.
I just wanna make sure that you are ready
to use the tools correctly to maximize learning potential.
So in this course, I will be speaking at my normal speed,
but if you think I am too slow,
you can speed me up up to 2X.
Oppositely, if you think I speak too fast,
you can decrease my speed up to 0.5X.
Also, I've made sure that this course
has professional subtitles that you can enable
on the bottom right using the CC icon.
Finally, you can also use transcripts
to read alongside the video if that helps you
maximize your learning.
At some point during the course,
you Udemy will ask you for some feedback.
If you are not ready to give a rating yet,
click on Ask Me Later.
Else, you can select a star rating for whatever you want
and then click on the star when you're done.
Here you can leave me a small message
telling me what you like about this course
and what you want me to improve.
When you're done, click on Save and Continue
and you can go ahead with this course.
I wanna say, your ratings are super important for me
and for new students, so please make sure you leave one
when your ready, okay?
That's all, I will see you in the next lecture.