Hi and welcome, my name is Stephane Maarek,
and I will be your instructor for this course.
I'm delighted to have you here,
I really hope that you will enjoy this course
and that you will go all the way through with it.
So, this is just a two-minute introduction
so that you get to know me,
and then we'll hop right into the course.
I'm French, so if you hear a small accent,
this is where it comes from,
it's the sweet country of France.
But I've also lived in the United States, in Australia,
and now in Portugal.
My expertise is going to be around AWS certifications
and Apache Kafka.
Why?
Well because in my career,
I've had the chance to be a data analyst,
a big data engineer, a developer, and a solutions architect.
Well, obviously nowadays I'm a teacher, I love to teach,
and this is my passion,
and I'm gonna help you achieve any goals you have
through online learning.
So before we get started with this course,
there are two ways you can connect with me.
The first place is on LinkedIn.
So this is where I will share some news about AWS
and the Kafka ecosystem.
This is where I announce new courses,
and this is where I congratulate my students.
So, for example, if you've completed the course,
or you passed a certification,
make a post on LinkedIn and tag me,
and I will make sure to congratulate you.
I love to see my students reach their goals,
this is my main motivation.
The second way is on Instagram.
So, Instagram is a big part of mine
that I've started several years ago.
So I love to travel the world,
and I dedicate some of my time to actually meet my students.
And to date, I've already met over 40 students.
So every time I meet students,
we'll have a chat about your goals,
about how the course helped you in your career,
and just general chat about life.
And at the end of it, I will make a post on Instagram.
So if you want to get the chance to meet me,
or to read about other students' stories,
then follow me on Instagram.
Finally, before starting this course,
I want you to set a goal.
By setting a goal,
you will have a much higher chance of finishing this course
and learning a lot.
So maybe you want to finish this course in three weeks,
that's perfect.
This is how you learn,
and this is how you will make the most out of this course.
And don't hesitate to go through the videos
as many times as needed.
This is what videos are used for.
If necessary, you can speed up the video or slow it down,
so it becomes easier for you to understand me.
So, that's it for me.
I hope you will enjoy the course,
and I will see you in the next lecture.
Happy learning!
(bright music fades)