As we will see in this course,
there are different types of cloud computing
and it is important for us to be able to recognize them.
The first one is called Infrastructure as a Service or IaaS.
This is to provide the building blocks for cloud IT.
With this IAAS, we're going to provide networking,
computers and data storage space in its raw form.
And using these building blocks, (indistinct)
building LEGOs,
We're going to be given a very high level of flexibility
and we can easily understand
how we can migrate from traditional on-premises IT
to the cloud.
Then we're gonna get platform as a service.
In this, we're going to remove the need
for your organization
to manage the underlying infrastructure,
and you can just focus on the deployment
and management of your applications.
And then one step even further is software
as a service or SaaS.
This is a completed product that is going to be run
and managed by the service provider.
So if you wanna compare all these things, well,
let's look at an example.
On premises, you're going to manage everything.
So your applications, your data, your runtime,
your middleware, the operating system, virtualization,
servers, storage and networking.
And that's a lot.
With IaaS, so infrastructure as a service, we're going
to manage the application, the data, the runtime,
the malware, and the OS.
But all the virtualization servers, storage
and networking are going to be managed by others.
And in our case, AWS.
With platform as a service, we manage even less.
So everything from the runtime
to the networking is managed by AWS.
And the only thing we care about when we use a platform
as a service is our application and our data.
And finally, well, if you're using software as a service,
everything is going to be managed by AWS.
So well, how does it translate?
Well, with IaaS, we can use Amazon EC2 on AWS,
but we have other services, such as Google Cloud,
Azure, Rackspace, Digital Ocean and Linode,
which will provide us a cloud computing infrastructure
as a service.
Platform as a service also exists on AWS
with Elastic Beanstalk.
And we'll see all the services obviously in this course.
And outside of AWS, we have Heroku, Google App Engine,
and Windows Azure.
For software as a service,
we'll also have this on AWS that represents many services
of AWS, for example, Rekognition where we want
to do some machine learning,
but we've been using it as well in the real world
with Google Apps, such as Gmail or Dropbox
or Zoom for your meetings.
So the Cloud has different flavors,
but one thing is common
is that the pricing is very different from what you know.
AWS has three pricing fundamentals
and it will follow the pay-as-you-go pricing model.
So for the compute, and that represents various services,
we're going to pay for the exact compute time.
For the storage, we're going to pay for the exact amount
of data stored in the cloud.
And for the networking, we're going
to only pay when the data leaves the cloud.
Any data that goes into the cloud is free.
And this solves the expensive issue of traditional IT
because now we only pay exactly what we need.
And so we have huge cost savings ahead of us.
So that's it for this lecture.
In the next lecture, we'll be having a deeper dive on AWS.