So welcome to the AWS Console Home.
And in this page, you can do a lot of things.
So first of all, let's have a look
at the top right corner of your screen,
right now, this is what's called the regions selector,
and right now I am in Northern Virginia,
US east one.
But it is advised for this course to
choose a region that is geographically close to you.
So because I'm in Europe, I'm actually close to Ireland.
So I can choose EU west one.
But if you are in other regions of the world, for example
if you're in Africa and you're close to Capetown
then choose this.
Of course you don't have to physically be
in that region to use that region, okay?
You can for example
choose whatever region makes sense for you.
So choose whatever is closest
and this will give you the lowest amount of latency.
Next in the console console, you will see a list
of recently visited services
and it should be empty for you.
And I just tried that one
so it's showing one right here for me.
On the bottom you get some information about AWS.
You get the health issues, if need be
and cost and usage info for your accounts
as well as tutorials to build a solution and so on.
So this webpage is actually changing a lot over timeless
changed a lot for the past two years.
And so it may not look exactly the same as you
and in case it looks very, very, very different.
I will rerecord this lecture.
Okay, so once we have this
we need to look at services of AWS.
And for this two options,
the first one is to go on the top left click on services
and you can either look at services
by alphabetical order, as you can see
there are a lot of services on AWS,
or by category for example, for compute
you will have all these services and so on.
But don't worry over time,
we will learn these services
and we don't have to navigate that page.
Another thing I really like is the search bar.
So you can actually type a service for example, route 53
and then it gives you search results.
So it gives you four services that match this query, okay?
And then within these services,
we can also have a look at features
and 13 features match them.
So we can directly jump into the domain names
of the route 53 service and it's a good thing.
We can also look at blogs, knowledge articles
documentations and so on.
So this is quite cool.
Let's go into route 53 now to have a look at this console.
So this one is very special because
on the top right hand side, it says global.
That means that this console
does not require a region selection.
And that is more of the exception than the rule,
but some services in AWS are where
it's called global services and no matter where you are
you're going to get the same view.
But if you switch services and you go, for example
to the EC two service,
this time on the top right hand side,
as you can see it says Ireland
because I chose the Ireland region.
And so based if I run this console in Ireland
or say in another region, for example, in Canada,
well my view is going to be different
in terms of the resources that I will see.
So that's why it's important for you to remain
within the same region for the entire duration
of this tutorial and this course.
The other thing you can look at
is called the AWS global infrastructure
that you can find on Google.
And this gives you a lot
of information around your services.
And one thing that is very important to look at
is the AWS regional services.
And it gives you the services list by region.
And so this is table,
and so for example, if in the course,
I talk about a service and do a hands on,
but it doesn't seem to be in your region,
you can check here and find the availability of services.
So for example, we can check a look,
have a look for Cape town
and see the services that are available in this region.
And if you don't see a service
maybe you need to switch a region
in of course the console,
to have access to it
because not all the services from AWS are in every region.
So that's it for this lecture,
I hope you liked it
and I will see you in the next lecture.